<opts>
    <opt>Alluvial fan
        <desc>Level (less than 1% slope) to very gently inclined, complex landform pattern of extremely low relief. The rapidly migrating alluvial stream channels are shallow to moderately deep, locally numerous, but elsewhere widely spaced. The channels form a centrifugal to divergent, integrated, reticulated to distributary pattern. The landform pattern includes areas that are bar plains, being aggraded or eroded by frequently active channelled stream flow, and other areas comprising terraces or stagnant alluvial plains with slopes that are greater than usual, formed by channelled stream flow but now relict. Incision in the upslope area may give rise to an erosional stream bed between scarps. Typical elements: stream bed, bar, plain. Compare with Sheet-flood fan and Pediment</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Alluvial plain
        <desc>Level landform pattern with extremely low relief. The shallow to deep alluvial stream channels are sparse to widely spaced, forming a unidirectional, integrated network. There may be frequently active erosion and aggradation by channelled and overbank stream flow, or the landforms may be relict from these processes. Typical elements: stream channel (stream bed and bank), plain (dominant). Common elements: bar, scroll, levee, backplain, swamp. Occasional elements: ox-bow, flood-out, lake. Included types of landform pattern are: flood plain, bar plain, meander plain, covered plain, anastomotic plain, delta, stagnant alluvial plain, terrace, terraced land.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Anastomotic plain
        <desc>Flood plain with slowly migrating, deep alluvial channels, usually moderately spaced, forming a divergent to unidirectional, integrated reticulated network. There is frequently active aggradation by overbank and channelled stream flow. Typical elements: stream channel (stream bed and bank), levee, backplain (dominant). Common element: swamp. Compare with other types under Alluvial plain and Flood plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Badlands
        <desc>Landform pattern of low to extremely low relief (less than 90 m) and steep to precipitous slopes, typically with numerous fixed, erosional stream channels which form a non-directional, integrated tributary network. There is continuously active erosion by collapse, landslide, sheet flow, creep and channelled stream flow. Typical elements: ridge (dominant), stream bed or gully. Occasional elements: summit surface, hillcrest, hillslope, talus. Compare with Mountains, Hills, Low hills, Rises and Plain</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Bar plain
        <desc>Flood plain with numerous rapidly migrating, shallow alluvial channels forming a unidirectional, integrated reticulated network. There is frequently active aggradation and erosion by channelled stream flow. Typical elements: stream bed, bar (dominant). Compare with other types under Alluvial plain and Flood plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Beach ridge plain
        <desc>Level to gently undulating landform pattern of extremely low relief on which stream channels are absent or very rare; it consists of relict, parallel beach ridges. Typical elements: beach ridge (co-dominant), swale (co-dominant). Common elements: beach, foredune, tidal creek. Compare with Chenier plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Chenier plain
        <desc>Level to gently undulating landform pattern of extremely low relief on which stream channels are very rare. The pattern consists of relict, parallel, linear ridges built up by waves, separated by, and built over, flats (mud flats) aggraded by tides or overbank stream flow. Typical elements: beach ridge (co-dominant), flat (co-dominant). Common elements: tidal flat, swamp, beach, foredune, tidal creek. Compare with Beach ridge plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Covered plain
        <desc>Flood plain with slowly migrating, deep alluvial channels, usually widely spaced and forming a unidirectional, integrated non-tributary network. There is frequently active aggradation by overbank stream flow. Typical elements: stream channel (stream bed and bank), levee, backplain (dominant). Common element: swamp. Compare with other types under Alluvial plain and Flood plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Delta
        <desc>Flood plain projecting into a sea or lake, with slowly migrating, deep alluvial channels, usually moderately spaced, typically forming a divergent, integrated distributary network. This landform is aggraded by frequently active overbank and channelled stream flow that is modified by tides. Typical elements: stream channel (stream bed and bank), levee, backplain (co-dominant), swamp (co-·dominant), lagoon (co-dominant). Common elements: beach ridge, swale, beach, estuary, tidal creek. Compare with other types under Alluvial plain, Flood plain and Chenier plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Dunefield
        <desc>Level to rolling landform pattern of very low or extremely low relief without stream channels, built up or locally excavated, eroded or aggraded by wind. Typical elements: dune or dunecrest, duneslope, swale, blow-out, risecrest, residual rise, riseslope. Common elements: hummocky dune, barchan dune, parabolic dune, linear dune. Included types of landform pattern are: longitudinal dunefield, parabolic dunefield</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Escarpment
        <desc>Steep to precipitous landform pattern forming a linearly extensive, straight or sinuous, inclined surface, which separates terrains at different altitudes; a plateau is commonly above the escarpment. Relief within the landform pattern may be high (hilly) or low (planar). The upper margin is often marked by an included cliff or scarp. Typical elements: hillcrest, hillslope, cliff­ footslope. Common elements: cliff, scarp, scarp-footslope, talus, footslope, alcove. Occasional element: stream bed.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Flood plain
        <desc>Alluvial plain characterised by frequently active erosion and aggradation by channelled or overbank stream flow. Unless otherwise specified, 'frequently active' is to mean that flow has an Average Recurrence Interval of 50 years or less. Typical elements: stream channel (stream bed and bank), plain (dominant). Common elements: bar, scroll, levee, backplain, swamp. Occasional elements: ox-bow, flood-out, scroll. Included types of landform pattern are: bar plain, meander plain, covered plain, anastomotic plain. Related relict landform patterns are: stagnant alluvial plain, terrace, terraced land (partly relict).</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Hills
        <desc>Landform pattern of high relief (90-300 m) with gently inclined to precipitous slopes. Fixed, shallow, erosional stream channels, closely to very widely spaced, form a non-directional or convergent, integrated tributary network. There is continuously active erosion by wash and creep and, in some cases, rarely active erosion by landslides. Typical elements: hillcrest, hillslope (dominant), drainage depression, stream bed. Common elements: footslope, alcove, valley flat, gully. Occasional elements: tor, summit surface, scarp, landslide, talus, bench, terrace, doline. Compare with Mountains, Low hills, Rises and Plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Karst
        <desc>Landform pattern of unspecified relief and slope (for specification use the terms in Table 5, e.g. 'Karst rolling hills') typically with fixed, deep, erosional stream channels forming a non-directional, disintegrated tributary pattern and many closed depressions without stream channels. It is eroded by continuously active solution and rarely active collapse, the products being removed through underground channels. Typical elements: hillcrest, hillslope (dominant), doline. Common elements: summit surface, valley flat, plain, alcove, drainage depression, stream channel, scarp, footslope, landslide. Occasional element: talus.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Lacustrine plain
        <desc>Level landform pattern with extremely low relief formerly occupied by a lake but now partly or completely dry. It is relict after aggradation by waves and by deposition of material from suspension and solution in standing water. The pattern is usually bounded by wave-formed features such as cliffs, rock platforms, beaches, berms and lunettes. These may be included or excluded. Typical element: plain. Common elements: beach, cliff. Occasional elements: rock platform, berm. Compare with Playa plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Longitudinal dunefield
        <desc>Dunefield characterised by long, narrow sand dunes and wide, flat swales. The dunes are oriented parallel with the direction of the prevailing wind, and in cross-section one slope is typically steeper than the other. Typical elements: dune or dunecrest, duneslope, swale, blow-out. Compare with Parabolic dunefield.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Low hills
        <desc>Landform pattern of low relief (30-90 m) and gentle to very steep slopes, typically with fixed, erosional stream channels, closely to very widely spaced, which form a non-directional or convergent, integrated tributary pattern. There is continuously active sheet flow, creep, and channelled stream flow. Typical elements: hillcrest, hillslope (dominant), drainage depression, stream bed. Common elements: footslope, alcove, valley flat, gully. Occasional elements: tor, summit surface, landslide, doline. Compare with Mountains, Hills, Rises and Plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Made land
        <desc>Landform pattern typically of very low or extremely low relief and with slopes either level or very steep. Sparse, fixed, deep, artificial stream channels form a non-directional, interrupted tributary pattern. The landform pattern is eroded and aggraded, and locally built up or excavated, by rarely active human agency. Typical elements: fill-top (dominant), cut-over surface, cut face, embankment, berm, trench. Common elements: mound, pit, dam</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Marine plain
        <desc>Plain eroded or aggraded by waves, tides, or submarine currents, and aggraded by deposition of material from suspension and solution in sea water, elevated above sea level by earth movements or eustasy, and little modified by subaerial agents such as stream flow or wind. Typical element: plain. Occasional elements: dune, stream channel.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Meander plain
        <desc>Plain eroded or aggraded by waves, tides, or submarine currents, and aggraded by deposition of material from suspension and solution in sea water, elevated above sea level by earth movements or eustasy, and little modified by subaerial agents such as stream flow or wind. Typical element: plain. Occasional elements: dune, stream channel</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Mountains
        <desc>Landform pattern of very high relief (greater than 300 m) with moderate to precipitous slopes and fixed, erosional stream channels that are closely to very widely spaced and form a non-directional or diverging, integrated tributary network. There is continuously active erosion by collapse, landslide, sheet flow, creep, and channelled stream flow. Typical elements: hillcrest, hillslope (dominant), stream bed. Common elements: talus, landslide, alcove, valley flat, scarp. Occasional elements: cirque, footslope. Compare with Hills, Low hills, Rises and Plain</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Parabolic dunefield
        <desc>Dunefield characterised by sand dunes with a long, scoop-shaped form, convex in the downwind direction so that its trailing arms point upwind; the ground plan, when developed, approximates the form of a parabola. Where many parabolic dunes have been active, the trailing arms give the impression of a longitudinal dunefield. Typical elements: dune or dunecrest, duneslope, swale, blow-out. Compare with Longitudinal dunefield.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Pediment
        <desc>Gently inclined to level (less than 1%) landform pattern of extremely low relief, typically with numerous rapidly migrating, very shallow incipient stream channels, which form a centrifugal to diverging, integrated reticulated pattern. It is underlain by bedrock, eroded, and locally aggraded, by frequently active channelled stream flow or sheet flow, with subordinate wind erosion. Pediments characteristically lie downslope from adjacent hills with markedly steeper slopes. Typical elements: pediment, plain, stream bed. Compare with Sheet-flood fan and Alluvial fan</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Pediplain
        <desc>Level to very gently inclined landform pattern with extremely low relief and no stream channels, eroded by barely active sheet flow and wind. Largely relict from more effective erosion by stream flow in incipient stream channels as on a pediment. (Described by King 1953.) Typical element: plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Peneplain
        <desc>Level to very gently inclined landform pattern with extremely low relief and no stream channels, eroded by barely active sheet flow and wind. Largely relict from more effective erosion by stream flow in incipient stream channels as on a pediment. Typical element: plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Plain
        <desc>Level to undulating or, rarely, rolling landform pattern of extremely low relief (less than 9 m). Compare with Mountains, Hills, Low hills and Rises.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Plateau
        <desc>Level to rolling landform pattern of plains, rises or low hills standing above a cliff, scarp or escarpment that extends around a large part of its perimeter. A bounding scarp or cliff landform element may be included or excluded; a bounding escarpment would be an adjacent landform pattern. Typical elements: plain, summit surface, cliff. Common elements: hillcrest, hillslope, drainage depression, rock flat, scarp. Occasional element: stream channel.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Playa plain
        <desc>Level landform pattern with extremely low relief, typically without stream channels, aggraded by rarely active sheet flow and modified by wind, waves, and soil phenomena. Typical elements: playa, lunette, plain. Compare with Lacustrine plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Rises
        <desc>Landform pattern of very low relief (9-30 m) and very gentle to steep slopes. The fixed, erosional stream channels are closely to very widely spaced and form a non-directional to convergent, integrated or interrupted tributary pattern. The pattern is eroded by continuously active to barely active creep and sheet flow. Typical elements: hillcrest, hillslope (dominant), footslope, drainage depression, riseslope. Common elements: valley flat, stream channel. Occasional elements: gully, fan, tor. Compare with Mountains, Hills, Low hills and Plain.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Sand plain
        <desc>Level to gently undulating landform pattern of extremely low relief and without channels; formed possibly by sheet flow or stream flow, but now relict and modified by wind action. Typical element: plain. Occasional elements: dune, playa, lunette.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Sheet-flood fan
        <desc>Level (less than 1% slope) to very gently inclined landform pattern of extremely low relief with numerous rapidly migrating, very shallow incipient stream channels forming a divergent to unidirectional, integrated or interrupted reticulated pattern. The pattern is aggraded by frequently active sheet flow and channelled stream flow, with subordinate wind erosion. Typical elements: plain, stream bed. Compare with Alluvial fan and Pediment.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Stagnant alluvial plain
        <desc>Alluvial plain on which erosion and aggradation by channelled and overbank stream flow is barely active or inactive because of reduced water supply, without apparent incision or channel enlargement that would lower the level of stream action. Typical elements: stream channel (stream bed and bank), plain (dominant). Common elements: bar, scroll, levee, backplain, swamp. Occasional elements: ox-bow, flood-out, lake. Compare with Flood plain and Terrace.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Terrace (alluvial)
        <desc>Former flood plain on which erosion and aggradation by channelled and overbank stream flow is barely active or inactive because deepening or enlargement of the stream channel has lowered the level of flooding. A pattern that has both a former flood plain and a significant, active flood plain, or that has former flood plains at more than one level, becomes terraced land. Typical elements: terrace plain (dominant), scarp, channel bench. Occasional elements: stream channel, scroll, levee.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Terraced land (alluvial)
        <desc>Landform pattern including one or more terraces and often a flood plain. Relief is low or very low (9-90 m). Terrace plains or terrace flats occur at stated heights above the top of the stream bank. Typical elements: terrace plains, terrace flats, scarps, scroll plain, stream channel. Occasional elements: stream channel, scroll, levee.</desc>
    </opt>

    <opt>Tidal flat
        <desc>Level landform pattern with extremely low relief and slowly migrating, deep alluvial stream channels, which form non-directional, integrated tributary patterns; it is aggraded by frequently active tides. Typical elements: plain (dominant), intertidal flat, supratidal flat, stream channel. Occasional elements: lagoon, dune, beach ridge, beach.</desc>
    </opt>
</opts>
