<opts>
    <opt>Anthropogenic elements
        <opt>Berm-human
            <desc>(i) short, very gently inclined to level minimal mid-slope in an embankment or cut face, eroded or aggraded by human activity.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Cut face
            <desc>Slope eroded by human activity</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Cut over surface
            <desc>Flat eroded by human activity</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Dam
            <desc>Ridge built up by human activity so as to close a depression</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Embankment
            <desc>Ridge or slop built up by human activity</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Fill-top
            <desc>Flat aggraded by human activity</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Mound
            <desc>Hillock built up by human activity</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Pit
            <desc>Closed depression excavated by human activity.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Trench
            <desc>Open depression excavated by human activity</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Cliff and scarp elements
        <opt>Breakaway
            <desc>Steep maximal mid-slope or upper slope, generally comprising both a very short scarp (free face) that is often bare rockland, and a stony scarp-footslope (debris slope); often standing above a pediment.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Cliff
            <desc>Very wide, cliffed (greater than 72°) maximal slope usually eroded by gravitational fall as a result of erosion of the base by various agencies; sometimes built up by marine organisms (cf. Scarp).</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Cliff-footslope
            <desc>Slope situated below a cliff, with its contours generally parallel to the line of the cliff, eroded by sheet wash or water-aided mass movement, and aggraded locally by collapsed material from above</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Landslide
            <desc>Moderately inclined to very steep slope, eroded in the upper part and aggraded in the lower part by water-aided mass movement, characterised by irregular hummocks.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Scarp
            <desc>Very wide, steep to precipitous maximal slope eroded by gravity, water-aided mass movement or sheet flow (cf. Cliff).</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Scarp-footslope
            <desc>Waning or minimal slope situated below a scarp, with its contours generally parallel to the line of the scarp.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Summit surface
            <desc>Very wide, level to gently inclined crest with abrupt margins, commonly eroded by water-aided mass movement or sheet wash.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Talus
            <desc>Moderately inclined or steep waning lower slope, consisting of rock fragments aggraded by gravity.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Coastal and estuarine elements
        <opt>Beach
            <desc>Short, low, very wide slope, gently or moderately inclined, built up or eroded by waves, forming the shore of a lake or sea</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>coastal and estuarine elements
        <opt>Beach ridge
            <desc>Very long, nearly straight, low ridge, built up by waves and usually modified by wind. A beach ridge is often a relict feature remote from the beach</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Berm
            <desc>(ii) flat built up by waves above a beach.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Coastal and estuarine elements
        <opt>Estuary
            <desc>Stream channel close to its junction with a sea or lake, where the action of channelled stream flow is modified by tide and waves. The width typically increases downstream</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Reef flat
            <desc>Flat built up to sea level by marine organisms.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Dune and swale elements
        <opt>Barchan dune
            <desc>A crescent-shaped dune with tips extending leeward (downwind), making this side concave and the windward (upwind) side convex. Barchan dunes tend to be arranged in chains extending in the dominant wind direction.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Dune
            <desc>Moderately inclined to very steep ridge or hillock built up by the wind. This element may comprise dunecrest and duneslope.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Dunecrest
            <desc>Crest built up or eroded by the wind (see Dune)</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Duneslope
            <desc>Slope built up or eroded by the wind (see Dune)</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Foredune
            <desc>Very long, nearly straight, moderately inclined to very steep ridge built up by the wind from material from an adjacent beach.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Hummocky
            <desc>Weakly oriented dune. Very gently to moderately inclined rises or hillocks built up or eroded by wind and lacking distinct orientation or regular pattern</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Linear or longitudinal dune
            <desc>Seif. Large, sharp-crested, elongated, longitudinal (linear) dune or chain of sand dunes, oriented parallel, rather than transverse (perpendicular), to the prevailing wind. (Not to be confused with the trailing arms of parabolic dunes.)</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Lunette
            <desc>Elongated, gently curved, low ridge built up by wind on the margin of a playa, typically with a moderate, wave- modified slope towards the playa and a gentle outer slope.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Parabolic dune
            <desc>Sand dune with a long, scoop-shaped form, convex in the downwind direction so that its horns point upwind, whose ground plan approximates the form of a parabola. The dunes left behind can be referred to as trailing arms. Where many such dunes have traversed an area, these can give the appearance of linear dunes.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Swale
            <desc>(i) linear, level-floored open depression excavated by wind, or left relict between ridges built up by wind or waves, or built up to a lesser height than them. (ii) long, curved open or closed depression left relict between scrolls built up by channelled stream flow.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Eroded, depressed or deflated elements
        <opt>Alcove
            <desc>Moderately inclined to very steep, short open depression with concave cross-section, eroded by collapse, landslides, creep or surface wash.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Crater
            <desc>Steep to precipitous closed depression excavated by explosions due to volcanism, human action, or impact of an extraterrestrial object</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Deflation basin
            <desc>Basin excavated by wind erosion which removes loose material, commonly above a resistant or wet layer.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Drainage depression
            <desc>Level to gently inclined, long, narrow, shallow open depression with smoothly concave cross-section, rising to moderately inclined side slopes, eroded or aggraded by sheet wash.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Playa
            <desc>Large, shallow, level-floored closed depression, intermittently water-filled, but mainly dry due to evaporation, bounded as a rule by flats aggraded by sheet flow and channelled stream flow.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Solution doline
            <desc>Steep-sided, circular or elliptical closed depression, commonly funnel-shaped, characterised by subsurface drainage and formed by dissolution of the surface or underlying bedrock.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Eroded, excavated and dissolved elements
        <opt>Blow-out
            <desc>Usually small, open or closed depression excavated by the wind</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Estuarine and tidal elements
        <opt>Tidal creek
            <desc>Intermittently water-filled open depression in parts eroded, excavated, built up and aggraded by channelled tide-water flow; type of stream channel characterised by a rapid increase in width downstream.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Intertidal flat
            <desc>large flat subject to inundation by water that is usually salt or brackish, aggraded by tides. An intertidal flat (ITF) is frequently inundated; a supratidal flat (STF) is seldom inundated</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Supratidal flat
            <desc>large flat subject to inundation by water that is usually salt or brackish, aggraded by tides. An intertidal flat (ITF) is frequently inundated; a supratidal flat (STF) is seldom inundated</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Fresh water elements
        <opt>Lagoon
            <desc>Closed depression filled with water that is typically salt or brackish, bounded at least in part by forms aggraded or built up by waves or reef-building organisms.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Lake
            <desc>Large, water-filled closed depression.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Swamp
            <desc>almost level, closed or almost closed depression with a seasonal or permanent watertable at or above the surface, commonly aggraded by overbank stream flow and sometimes biological (peat) accumulation</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Hill and rise elements
        <opt>Bench
            <desc>Short, gently or very gently inclined minimal mid-slope element eroded or aggraded by any agent.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Footslope
            <desc>Moderately to very gently inclined waning lower slope resulting from aggradation or erosion by sheet flow, earth flow or creep (cf. Pediment).</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Hillcrest
            <desc>Very gently inclined to steep crest, smoothly convex, eroded mainly by creep and sheet wash. A typical element of mountains, hills, low hills and rises</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Hillslope
            <desc>Gently inclined to precipitous slope, commonly simple and maximal, eroded by sheet wash, creep or water-aided mass movement. A typical element of mountains, hills, low hills and rises</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Pediment
            <desc>Large, gently inclined to level (&amp;amp;lt;1%) waning lower slope, with slope lines inclined in a single direction, or somewhat convergent or divergent, eroded or sometimes slightly aggraded by sheet flow (cf. Footslope). It is underlain by bedrock.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Residual rise
            <desc>Hillock of very low to extremely low relief (&amp;amp;lt;30 m) and very gentle to steep slopes. This term is used to refer to an isolated rise surrounded by other landforms.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Risecrest
            <desc>Crest of hillock of very low to extremely low relief (&amp;amp;lt;30 m)</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Riseslope
            <desc>Slope of hillock of very low to extremely low relief (&amp;amp;lt;30 m).</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Tumulus
            <desc>Hillock heaved up by volcanism. In other settings, built up by human activity at a burial site.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Plain and gully elements
        <opt>Gully
            <desc>Open depression with short, precipitous walls and moderately inclined to very gently inclined floor or small stream channel, eroded by channelled stream flow and consequent collapse and water-aided mass movement.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Valley flat
            <desc>Small, gently inclined to level flat, aggraded or sometimes eroded by channelled or overbank stream flow, typically enclosed by hillslopes; a miniature alluvial plain landform pattern</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Rock and scald elements
        <opt>Rock flat
            <desc>Flat of bare consolidated rock, ususally eroded by sheet wash</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Rock platform
            <desc>Flot of consolidated rock eroded by waves</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Scald
            <desc>Flat, bare of vegetation, from which soil has been eroded or excavated by surface wash or wind.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Tor
            <desc>Steep to precipitous hillock, typically convex, with a surface mainly of bare rock, either coherent or comprising subangular to rounded, large boulders (exhumed core-stones, also themselves called tors) separated by open fissures; eroded by sheet wash or water-aided mass movement.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
    <opt>Stream and floodplain elements
        <opt>Backplain
            <desc>Large flat resulting from aggradation by overbank stream flow at some distance from the stream channel and in some cases biological (peat) accumulation; often characterised by a high watertable and the presence of swamps or lakes; part of a covered plain landform pattern.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Bank
            <desc>Stream bank. Very short, very wide slope, moderately inclined to precipitous, forming the marginal upper parts of a stream channel and resulting from erosion or aggradation by channelled stream flow</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Bar
            <desc>Stream bar. Elongated, gently to moderately inclined, low ridge built up by channelled stream flow; part of a stream bed.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Channel bench
            <desc>Flat at the margin of a stream channel aggraded and partly eroded by overbank and channelled stream flow; an incipient flood plain. Channel benches have been referred to as &amp;#x27;low terraces&amp;#x27;, but the term &amp;#x27;terrace&amp;#x27; should be restricted to landform patterns above the influence of active stream flow.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Fan
            <desc>Large, gently inclined to level element with radial slope lines inclined away from a point, resulting from aggradation, or occasionally from erosion, by channelled, often braided, stream flow, or possibly by sheet flow.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Flood-out
            <desc>Flat inclined radially away from a point on the margin or at the end of a stream channel, aggraded by overbank stream flow, or by channelled stream flow associated with channels developed within the overbank flow; part of a covered plain landform pattern.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Levee
            <desc>Very long, low, narrow, nearly level, sinuous ridge immediately adjacent to a stream channel, built up by overbank flow. Levees are built, usually in pairs bounding the two sides of a stream channel, at the level reached by frequent floods. This element is part of a covered plain landform pattern. For an artificial levee, use Embankment. See also Prior stream.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Ox-bow
            <desc>Long, curved, commonly water-filled closed depression eroded by channelled stream flow but closed as a result of aggradation by channelled or overbank stream flow during the formation of a meander plain landform pattern. The floor of an ox-bow may be more or less aggraded by overbank stream flow, wind, and biological (peat) accumulation.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Prior stream
            <desc>Long, generally sinuous, low ridge built up from materials originally deposited by stream flow along the line of a former stream channel. The landform element may include a depression marking the old stream bed, and relict levees.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Scroll
            <desc>Long, curved, very low ridge built up by channelled stream flow and left relict by channel migration. Part of a meander plain landform pattern.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Scroll plain
            <desc>Large flat resulting from aggradation by channelled stream flow as a stream migrates from side to side; the dominant element of a meander plain landform pattern. This landform element may include occurrences of scroll, swale and ox-bow.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Stream bed
            <desc>linear, generally sinuous open depression forming the bottom of a stream channel, eroded and locally excavated, aggraded or built up by channelled stream flow. Parts that are built up include bars.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Stream channel
            <desc>Linear, generally sinuous open depression, in parts eroded, excavated, built up and aggraded by channelled stream flow. This element comprises stream bed and banks.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Terrace flat
            <desc>Small flat aggraded or eroded by channelled or overbank stream flow, standing above a scarp and no longer frequently inundated; a former valley flat or part of a former flood plain.</desc>
        </opt>
        <opt>Terrace plain
            <desc>Large or very large flat aggraded by channelled or overbank stream flow, standing above a scarp and no longer frequently inundated; part of a former flood plain.</desc>
        </opt>
    </opt>
</opts>
